

"Always walk through life as if you have something new to learn and you will"

# Summary\_

A third year undergraduate student interested in solving problems in quantum information science. Experienced in quantum computation, quantum algorithm and communication with noise models, quantum machine learning and quantum simulation along with the fundamentals of physics.

# **Education**

### Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee

Roorkee, India

B.Tech in Engineering Physics

June 2018 - May 2022

• CGPA: 9.398

#### The Cathedral and John Connon School

Mumbai, India

GRADE 12(ISC)

2018 - Walingal

• Percentage: 98.5%

#### The Cathedral and John Connon School

Mumbai, India

GRADE 10(ICSE)

2010

· Percentage: 95.2%

# **Experience**

#### **Harish-Chandra Research Institute**

Allahabad,India

RESEARCH INTERN

Jul. 2020 - Present

- Research internship under the guidance of Prof. Arun K Pati.
- · Working on implementing noise models: phase flip, bit flip on the Probabilistic Quantum Teleportation Protocol
- Implemented and extended papers on teleportation using MATLAB

### Qiskit Global Summer School(IBM)

Global(Online)

SUMMER STUDENT

Jul. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- A three-week intensive summer school organised by the qiskit community(IBM) on a global platform.
- The school focused on teaching a broad range of topics: from qubits and bloch sphere to quantum chemistry and superconducting qubits.
- Selected as a lab student and was able to implement several algorithms: Grover's algorithm, Shor's algorithm and Deutsch-Jozsa algorithms along with implementation of rabi waves.
- · Participated and completed the qiskit final project based on the most ideal simulation of the LiH molecule using VQE.

# Projects\_

## **Classification of Quantum Correlations and Channels**

India

PROJECT MEMBER AT BOSE.X

Sept 2020 - Present

- Working on preparing a complete mathematical formulation and computational algorithm for the classification of different quantum channels and correlations in open systems.
- Utilities: Qiskit, Qutip

### Classification of the MNIST dataset using VQC

India(Online,

QISKIT CHALLENGE INDIA PROJECT

Sept 2020 - Sept 2020

- Implemented a classification algorithm using Variational Quantum Classifier to distinguish between the digits 4 and 9 from the handwritten MNIST dataset.
- Worked on making a custom feature map and variation circuit with different degrees of entanglement.
- · Able to achieve an efficiency of 80.9%

October 26, 2020 Tanya Garg · Résumé 1

### Simulation of LiH molecule using VQE on Qiskit

Global(Online)

SUMMER SCHOOL PROJECT

Aug. 2020 - Aug. 2020

• Implemented the ideal simulation of the LiH molecule by varying the initial state, variational form, simulator backend, noise model and the mapping type.

• Able to achieve an efficiency of 98.3%

#### Ultra high power short laser pulses of 1550nm

Roorkee, India Jun. 2019 - Jul. 2019

SUMMER PROJECT

- · Worked under the guidance of Prof. Vipul Rastogi, Department of Physics, IIT Roorkee, in the photonics lab.
- Worked on finding the pulse power, pulse duration and the intensity for the laser ablation of aluminium, copper and iron using 1550nm from a
  literature review
- Compared the values of the threshold fluence for the above-mentioned metals at different pulse duration.

Solar Sails Roorkee, India

PROJECT AT SRISHTI Nov. 2018 - March. 2019

- Got to study and present the topic of Solar Sails (method of spacecraft propulsion) at Srishti 2019, the annual technical exhibition of IIT Roorkee , under the guidance of the Physics and Astronomy Club
- After a literature review, a poster was made and presented.

## Honors & Awards

2020 **Qiskit Challenge India**, Team ranked in the top 10 from a pool of more than 500 teams

2019 **ENCORE Award**, Received the 2019 award given to 2nd yearites for excellence in all-round performance

IITR Heritage Excellence Award, Received the 2019 award given to one student from each year for

excellence in all-round performance

2018 INSPIRE, Eligible for the 2018 award for being in the top 1% of the ISC Board in Grade 12

## Skills

Programming Languages Python, JAVA

**Utilities** Git, Linux Shell

Relevant Courses (online) Introduction to Quantum Computing, Quantum Physics I and II, Understanding Research Methods

Design and Analysis of Algorithm, Machine Learning

Relevant Courses (offline) Mathematics-I (Linear Algebra and Calculus), Optimisation Techniques, Electromagnetic Theory,

Quantum Mechanics, Quantum Computing, Mathematical Physics, Digital and Analog ELectronics

# **Extracurricular Activity**

#### Athletics team, IIT Roorkee

Roorkee, India Jun. 2018 - Present

MEMBER AND JOINT SECRETARY SINCE 2019

- Member and former Vice Captain of the team.
- A thrower. Participated in various tournaments at IIT Kanpur and member of the Inter IIT Contingent for 2018 and 2019.
- · Won several medals including a bronze medal(among participants from 23 IITs) in shotput in Inter IIT 2019 held at IIT Kharagpur.

### Kshitij: The Literary Magazine

Roorkee, India

Aug. 2018 - Present

MEMBER AND CO-ORDINATOR SINCE 2020

- The bilingual literary magazine of the campus of IIT Roorkee
- · Aimed at promoting the literary culture among the students.
- · Organised and performed at Eunoia 2019, the annual slam poetry event of IITR.
- · Worked on various articles as a member of the English Editorial team.